让我们再次考虑我们有一个相机看着一个物体的情况。再来一次
Let's consider again the situation where we have a camera looking at an object. Once again
这是一个球。我们将坐标C附加到相机，我们的坐标为
it's a ball. We attach a coordinate C to the camera and we have the coordinate of
球相对于相机坐标系表示。
the ball expressed with respect to the camera coordinate frame.
我们将介绍一个新的符号，即F帽，它是a的焦距
We're going to introduce a new symbol, which is F hat, and it is the focal length of a
透镜，以米为单位，除以由像素给出的像素的尺寸
lens, which is in units of meters, divided by the dimensions of the pixel given by the
希腊字母Rho。现在Rho具有每像素米的单位，因此该比率具有像素单位。
Greek letter Rho. Now Rho has units of meters per pixel, so the ratio has got units of pixels.
然后，F帽是表示镜头焦距而不是表达的另一种方式
F hat then is another way of representing the focal length of a lens instead of expressing
以米为单位，我们以像素为单位表示，这对我们来说非常有用。
it in units of meters, we express it in units of pixels and this can be very useful to us shortly.
我们可以将球的位置投影到图像平面中，我们将其表示为
We can project the position of the ball into the image plane, and we represent that by
坐标U，V，任何一个都没有新的东西。我要简化表示法
coordinate U, V, there is nothing new in any of this. I'm going to simplify the notation
并将三维空间中球的位置称为大写字母X，大写字母Y，大写字母Z和
and refer to the position of the ball in 3D space as capital X, capital Y, capital Z and
现在我们可以用这种方式在图像平面上写出球投影的坐标，
now we can write the coordinates of the projection of the ball in the image plane in this fashion,
使用符号X，Y和Z以及Fhat，记住是镜头表达的焦距
using the symbols X, Y and Z and F hat, which remember is the focal length of the lens expressed
以像素为单位。
in units of pixels.
现在让我们考虑相机正在移动。我们要把它绑在一只兔子身上。相机
Now let's consider that the camera is moving. We're going to strap it to a rabbit. The camera
现在能够以速度移动，我们可以通过三个向量Vx，Vy和
now is able to move with a velocity, which we can express by a three vector Vx, Vy and
Vz，它也能够旋转。我们可以表达它的旋转速度，因为它是有角度的
Vz and it's also able to rotate. And we can express its rotational velocity, as it's angular
组分OmegaX，OmegaY和OmegaZ的速度。
velocity with components Omega X, Omega Y and Omega Z.
那么现在发生了什么？那么我们现在需要考虑球的投射
Well what happens now? Well we now need to think about the projection of the ball in
图像平面不仅具有位置U，V，而且还具有图像中的速度
the image plane having not just a location U, V but it's also got a velocity in the image
平面，我们用U点和V点代表。
plane, which we'll represent by U dot and V dot.
现在有一个非常着名的表达方式，它将摄像机的速度与摄像机的速度联系起来
Now there's a very well known expression that relates the velocity of the camera to the
像平面中的像素速度和这两个量通过雅可比矩阵相关联
pixel velocity in the image plane and these two quantities are related by a Jacobian matrix
我们之前在机器人MOOC中遇到过JacobianMatrices。
and we have come across Jacobian Matrices before in the robotics MOOC.
这里的雅可比矩阵是一个二乘六矩阵，它与摄像机速度和此相关
The Jacobian matrix here is a two by six matrix, which relates the camera velocity and this
是相机的空间速度，它具有平移分量和旋转
is the cameras spatial velocity which has got a translational component and a rotational
零件。乘以这个二乘六矩阵，给出我们在图像平面上的速度。
component. Multiplied by this two by six matrix, to give us the velocity in the image plane.
图像中该点似乎移动的速度。
The velocity at which that point in the image appears to move.
这是我们的MATLAB工作区，我们已经创建了一个相机对象。我要去计算
Here's our MATLAB workspace and we have already created a camera object. I'm going to compute
将雅可比图像放入工作空间变量J并且这样做我将使用visjac_p
the image Jacobian into the workspace variable J and to do that I am going to use the visjac_p
方法，这是一个点特征的视觉雅可比的简称，它是相机的一种方法
method, that's short for visual Jacobian for a point feature, it's a method of the camera
对象，我将传递我感兴趣的图像平面点的坐标
object and I'm going to pass in the coordinate of the image plane point that I'm interested
in和那是600,600，它必须是列向量，所以我在那里放了一个撇号
in and that's at 600, 600, its got to be column vector, so I put an apostrophe there and
它对应于距离相机5米的世界点。
it corresponds to a world point that's five meters away from the camera.
所以这是视觉雅各布的;它是一个2乘6的矩阵。如果我乘以雅可比图像
So here's the visual Jacobian; it is a 2 by 6 matrix. If I multiply the image Jacobian
通过空间速度矢量，让我们考虑X方向的单位速度，没有速度
by a spatial velocity vector, let's consider a unit velocity in the X direction, no velocity
在Y或Z并且没有旋转并且它是列向量，那么图像平面点将继续
in Y or Z and no rotation and it's a column vector, then the image plane point is going
在负U方向以每秒160像素的速度移动，它不会移动
to move at 160 pixels per second in the negative U direction and it's not going to move at
一切都在V方向。
all in the V direction.
让我们尝试不同的空间速度。让我们来看看如果它在世界上移动会发生什么
Let's try a different spatial velocity. Let's look at what happens if it moves in the world
Y方向，我们看到它在图像平面上以负V方向以每秒160个像素移动。
Y direction, we see that it moves at 160 pixels per second in the negative V direction on the image plane.
让我们再看一个例子，我们将以单位速度移动摄像机
Let's just look at one more example and we will move the camera at unit velocity in the
Z方向;沿着光轴，我们看到现在的图像平面点
Z direction; that's along the optical axis and we see that now the image plane point
在U方向上以每秒17.6像素的速度移动，在V方向上以每秒17.6像素的速度移动。
is moving at 17.6 pixels per second in the U direction and 17.6 pixels per second in the V direction.